<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Appendix on HobbyFarm</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/appendix/</link><description>Recent content in Appendix on HobbyFarm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/appendix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deprecated &amp; Removed Features</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/appendix/deprecated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/appendix/deprecated/</guid><description>Deprecated Features The following features have been deprecated in HobbyFarm and will be removed in a future release.
Feature Deprecation Date Reason for Deprecation Terraform Provisioning October 2022 Compatibility, instability and performance issues Removed Features The following features have been completely removed from HobbyFarm.
Feature Removal Date Pull Request Reason RancherVM September 2023 #394 No longer maintained.</description></item><item><title>Helm Options</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/appendix/helm_options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/appendix/helm_options/</guid><description>This page contains a reference of the options available in the HobbyFarm Helm chart. Please visit the values.yaml file in the HobbyFarm repository for the most up-to-date list of options.
General Key Default Purpose insecure false Use insecure protocols. Useful for local development. Admin UI Options Key Default Purpose admin.image hobbyfarm/admin-ui:[version] Image used for admin-ui. admin.configMapName admin-config ConfigMap used to configure admin ui. admin.config.title HobbyFarm Administration Title of admin ui as seen in browser.</description></item><item><title>Provider Images</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/appendix/provider_images/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/appendix/provider_images/</guid><description>A provider image is a virtual machine image which exists on a 3rd party cloud provider, such as DigitalOcean or AWS. These images are used by HobbyFarm to deploy virtual machines per cloud environment. The provider image is used to determine the operating system, software, and configuration of the virtual machine deployed and managed by HobbyFarm.
Image Examples Provider Image Image Type AMI URL DigitalOcean ubuntu-20-04-x64 Ubuntu 20.04 LTS x64 DO Available Images AWS ami-0a6e38961e6e621b0 Ubuntu 20.</description></item><item><title>Special Markdown Syntax</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/appendix/markdown_syntax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/appendix/markdown_syntax/</guid><description>This page contains a reference of the special markdown syntax available in the scenario contents.
Code Syntax Highlighting You can enable syntax highlighting by providing a language to the codeblock. Providing the optional filename will display it together with the content
```&amp;lt;language&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;optional filename&amp;gt; code ``` For example
```md # Content ``` ```yaml:myfile.yaml yaml: highlight this #comment ``` Click-To-File Beginning with HobbyFarm 2.0.6 you can also enable users to create files directly with one click using the folowing syntax:</description></item></channel></rss>