<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Configuration on HobbyFarm</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/configuration/</link><description>Recent content in Configuration on HobbyFarm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/configuration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Settings</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/configuration/settings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/configuration/settings/</guid><description>The Settings page allows administrators to configure general settings for the HobbyFarm platform. To access the Settings page, log into the HobbyFarm Admin-UI and click the Configuration option in the top navigation menu. In the left navigation menu, click the Settings option.
Settings are divided into the following scopes:
Public The Public scope is used to configure settings which impact the HobbyFarm platform as a whole.
Setting Default Optional Description User UI MOTD none Yes A message to be displayed to users when logging into the HobbyFarm User UI.</description></item><item><title>VM Templates</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/configuration/vmtemplates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/configuration/vmtemplates/</guid><description>The VM Templates page allows administrators to configure templates for virtual machines used by HobbyFarm. These templates are used in by HobbyFarm Environments to create virtual machines on 3rd party platforms.
To access the Settings page, log into the HobbyFarm Admin-UI and click the Configuration option in the top navigation menu. In the left navigation menu, click the VM Templates option.
Creating a VM Template To create a new VM Template, click on the +NEW button in the top left corner of the page under the VM Templates heading.</description></item><item><title>Environments</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/configuration/environments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/configuration/environments/</guid><description>An Environment defines specific implementation details on how HobbyFarm connects to a provider, such as DigitalOcean or AWS, for scheduling virtual machines. An environment defines configuration information such as provider credentials, virtual machine templates to use, and the total capacity of virtual machines which can be deployed.
To access the Environments page, log into the HobbyFarm Admin-UI and click the Configuration option in the top navigation menu. In the left navigation menu, click the Environments option.</description></item><item><title>Provisioners</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/configuration/provisioners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/configuration/provisioners/</guid><description>In HobbyFarm, a provisioner is a Kubernetes resource used to define the specific implementation details on how HobbyFarm connects to a provider, such as DigitalOcean or AWS, for scheduling virtual machines. A provisioner defines configuration information such as provider credentials, virtual machine templates to use, and the total capacity of virtual machines which can be deployed.
Current Provisioners Below is a list of the provisioners currently supported by HobbyFarm. Please visit the links below for more information on each provisioner, including documentation on how to deploy and configure the provisioners.</description></item><item><title>Roles</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/configuration/roles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/configuration/roles/</guid><description>In Kubernetes, a Role is a set of permissions that can be assigned to a user or group of users. A Role can be assigned to a user or group of HobbyFarm users via a RoleBinding. HobbyFarm provides an interface for creating and managing HobbyFarm specific Roles via the Admin-UI.
To access the Roles page, log into the HobbyFarm Admin-UI and click the Configuration option in the top navigation menu. In the left navigation menu, click the Roles option.</description></item></channel></rss>