<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Installation on HobbyFarm</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/installation/</link><description>Recent content in Installation on HobbyFarm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/installation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prerequisites</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/installation/prerequisites/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/installation/prerequisites/</guid><description>The following prerequisites are required for installing HobbyFarm. Please ensure that all prerequisites are met before proceeding with the installation. Failure to do so may result in an unsuccessful installation.
Helm Helm v3 is required for deploying HobbyFarm. Please refer to the Helm documentation for instructions on installing Helm.
Kubernetes HobbyFarm is a Kubernetes-native application, using custom resources and controllers to manage the application. To run HobbyFarm, a Kubernetes cluster with an installed ingress controller is required.</description></item><item><title>Deployment</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/installation/deployment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/installation/deployment/</guid><description>The following steps will guide you through the deployment of HobbyFarm in a Kubernetes environment using Helm. Please ensure that all prerequisites are met before proceeding with the installation. Failure to do so may result in an unsuccessful installation.
Step 1: Add Helm Repository Using Helm, add the HobbyFarm repository and generate a values.yaml file for customization.
## Add the required Helm repository helm repo add hobbyfarm https://hobbyfarm.github.io/hobbyfarm ## Update your local Helm repository cache helm repo update ## List available versions of HobbyFarm helm search repo hobbyfarm/hobbyfarm ## Get the values.</description></item><item><title>Admin Account</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/installation/initial_admin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/docs/installation/initial_admin/</guid><description>Once you have installed HobbyFarm, an initial administrator account must be created. This account will be used to manage the HobbyFarm platform.
Step 1: Register a User Visit the newly deployed HobbyFarm UI at https://learn.{domain}.com and register a new user.
NOTE: If a different URL for the end-user learning interface was used, visit that URL instead.
Step 2: Verify the User As part of the deployment of HobbyFarm, new API resources are created in the cluster.</description></item></channel></rss>