<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contributing on HobbyFarm</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/contributing/</link><description>Recent content in Contributing on HobbyFarm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://hobbyfarm.github.io/contributing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backend Development</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/contributing/backend_development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/contributing/backend_development/</guid><description>HobbyFarm makes use of a backend service called Gargantua. Gargantua is a RESTful API written in Go. The following instructions will assist in setting up a local development environment for Gargantua.
The following instructions will assist in setting up a local development environment for Gargantua.
Requirements Gargantua is written in Go. To develop Gargantua, knowledge of Go is required.
The following tools are required to be installed:
Docker Docker Compose Plugin Setup The following instructions will assist in setting up a local development environment for Gargantua.</description></item><item><title>Frontend Development</title><link>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/contributing/frontend_development/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://hobbyfarm.github.io/contributing/frontend_development/</guid><description>HobbyFarm consists of two frontend applications: the primary user interface (ui) and the administrator user interface (admin-ui). The UI is the primary application users interact with. The Admin UI is a separate application used to manage the HobbyFarm backend.
The following instructions will assist in setting up a local development environment for HobbyFarm.
Requirements Both the UI and Admin UI are written in Angular. To develop either application, knowledge of Angular and Typescript is required.</description></item></channel></rss>